<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>PeetRonics' blog - Public Speaking</title><link href="http://peetronics.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://peetronics.com/feeds/public-speaking.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://peetronics.com/</id><updated>2019-11-13T21:00:00+00:00</updated><subtitle>All can be true!</subtitle><entry><title>What I Have Learned Today - #009</title><link href="http://peetronics.com/WhatIHaveLearnedToday-009.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-11-13T21:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-13T21:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Peet Michielsen</name></author><id>tag:peetronics.com,2019-11-13:/WhatIHaveLearnedToday-009.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reviewing abstracts for talks — learn from others&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="review testbash abstracts" src="http://peetronics.com/images/review-testbash-abstracts.png" width="80%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Reviewing abstracts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I have tweeted about the benefits of reviewing abstracts for talks. In this case the ones for upcoming &lt;em&gt;TestBashes&lt;/em&gt; from the &lt;em&gt;Ministry of Testing&lt;/em&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet" align="center"&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/peetronics/status/1108145209269993474"&gt;Tweet of peetronics/1108145209269993474&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It provides valuable feedback for the applicants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is an easy way to give back to the (testing) community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives you a sneak peek into what is current in the field of testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It gives you ideas for submitting your own abstracts (if you’ve got the ambition into public speaking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all lots of opportunities to &lt;strong&gt;learn&lt;/strong&gt;. I encourage everyone to get involved in this. Follow &lt;a href="https://www.ministryoftesting.com/testbash/review"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Reviewing and writing feedback&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to do this activity on a regular basis; once or twice a month, like tonight. I had some time set aside to go through a batch of abstracts. Finished quicker than I thought as after 6 or so proposals there were no more left for me to review 😅.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="message: There are no proposals to review at this time" src="http://peetronics.com/images/no-reviews.png" width="80%"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That aside, I want to focus on what I &lt;strong&gt;learn&lt;/strong&gt; from these kind of exercises. As well as the benefits laid out in the aforementioned bullet-points, doing an activity like this will sharpen your skills like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critically reading&lt;/strong&gt; a piece of text. Sometimes you grasp an abstract in a first read, but often it needs to be read two or more times to get an understanding of the applicant’s intent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making a judgement&lt;/strong&gt; based on what you’ve read. Once the proposal is understood, an assessment needs to be made, using predefined criteria (like: context, relevance, originality etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formulating constructive feedback&lt;/strong&gt;. And when the assessment is made, this needs to be relayed back to the organisation and author. And especially this is an area where I continue to learn. It’s harder than you think to write something that can be used by the recipient as input to improve upon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy learning!  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is part of a series of articles about “What I Have Learned Today”; acknowledging every day the thing I have learned. Feel free to read the other posts. all opinions in this article are my own and not necessarily represent the views of my employer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="Public Speaking"></category><category term="What I Have Learned Today"></category><category term="Ministry Of Testing"></category></entry></feed>